Tareq Aghabi

tareqaghabi@gmail.com | taghabi.github.io | +1 (514) 581 6653 | Relocating to the Middle East

PROFILE

Data Analyst and Industrial Engineer with 3+ years of experience in Tech Logistics, E-commerce, and Digital Operations, proficient in SQL, Python, R, Looker, Tableau, ERP Dynamics 365, JavaScript, Google Apps Script, Excel, HTML, and CSS. Canadian and Jordanian citizen, native in English and Arabic.

EDUCATION

Harvard University, School of Engineering and Applied Sciences

HarvardX

Professional Certificate in Data Science

February 2021

Relevant Coursework: SQL, Python, R, Visualization, Probability, Wrangling, Regression, Machine Learning & AI

Concordia University, School of Engineering and Computer Science

Montréal, QC

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering (BEng)

May 2019

Relevant Coursework: Operations Research, Stochastic Models, Simulation, Calculus, Probability & Statistics

Amman Baccalaureate School, Applied Sciences

Amman, JOD

International Baccalaureate Diploma Program (IBDP)

May 2014

• Relevant Coursework: Computer Science, Mathematics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Goodfood Market Corporation - Leading Canadian online grocery delivery

Montréal, QC

Operations Analyst – Big Data Analytics & Digital Operations

April 2021 – Present

- Promoted to Operations Analyst within an eight-month timeframe for exceeding goals and supporting company culture.
- Configured the weekly system changeover for over 1500 new SKU items in the Goodfood E-commerce backend database and ERP warehouse management system, determining multi-facility SKU picking & storage locations and inventory replenishment triggers based on analysis of order volume projections and operations cost analysis.
- Automated customer order data pull schedules from Looker into Google Sheets to develop an interfacility inventory replenishment analysis model using JavaScript, improving item replenishment availability and visibility by 50%.
- Strategically assigned over 3000 multi-facility SKU storage and picking locations data into the Goodfood E-commerce backend database and ERP warehouse management system using Microsoft SQL Server Studio queries.
- Created over 10 automated analysis tools and visualization dashboards for logging short ship data, managing labor cost, and tracking shipping carrier progress, informing daily item management decisions to senior directors and executives.

Production Supervisor – Supply Chain Operations

August 2020 – April 2021

- Utilized Excel to implement data cross-validation for recipe batch production requirements on 600+ batches, which reduced total production errors by 95%.
- Wrangled multiple recipe production datasets stored in Google Data Studio using Excel pivot tables to remodel and visualize datasets to allow operations and senior management to track the location and status of recipe batch production.
- Actively supervised workflow, delegated strategy and trained production and inventory teams of over 25 associates to maintain operational efficiency, increasing overall recipe pallet building productivity by 20%.

United Parcel Service – *Global shipping & logistics*

Montréal, QC

 $Industrial\ Engineering\ Specialist-Route\ Optimization\ Engineering\ Project\ Team$

April 2019 – May 2020

- Utilized UPS mapping and optimization software to plot and schedule delivery route information for over 70 training and verification rides on deployed driver groups, decreasing route delivery mileage by 15%.
- Extracted and manipulated route-specific statistics stored in UPS proprietary databases using Excel Visual Basic to generate over 25 technical reports, providing corporate-wide visibility to overall project deployment progress.
- Optimized and scheduled over 1800 driver and helper meetups in all regions of Montréal and Laval using UPS logistics software, resulting in an increase of 70 stops per package-car during peak season.
- Created a Master Operating Plan on the Data Acquisition department documenting the data collection and transformation methods for package processing at UPS, standardizing data processing operations and decreasing errors by 25%.

PROJECTS

Data Science Capstone

HarvardX October 2020 – January 2021

Cryptocurrency Forecast Capstone (HarvardX)

- Utilized R to implement supervised machine learning techniques for time series forecasts and anomaly detection on structured data, which explained model variability by 99%.
- Web scraped and wrangled Bitcoin and Ethereum historical data stored in an online database to remodel and visualize price prediction forecasts using linear regression and root mean square error.
- Compiled results and wrote a business report detailing value proposition and strategy for cryptocurrency investors.

Lean Manufacturing Design

Montréal, OC

Industrial Engineering Capstone (Concordia University)

September 2018 – April 2019

- Collaborated with 4 industrial engineers to design and implement a solution proposal for a Metal Die Manufacturer.
- Generated a user-friendly software interface using Excel Visual Basic to automate interdepartmental communication.
- Utilized operations research on CPLEX to optimize the facility layout of 10 inefficient machine setups within the stamping department, reducing overall lead time and decrease material handling costs 15%.

Additional SQL, Python, R and Tableau based Data Science projects can be viewed in my portfolio website.